Okay, we
are at time, so wait a few more minutes.
So should we dive in?
What do you think?
Hey! Dive in!
Go for it. Okay. Okay.
All right, so, everyone, thank you so much
for coming to the intro to scroll
Mason workshop.
Really happy to have you all here.
And really excited to share a little bit
about this tool I've been building.
But as well as talk about scroll
and more generally since scroll,
Mason is not just scroll
cinema like this tool I made,
but a bigger thing that I am excited
about in general.
So with that we can dive in.
So the very first thing
we'll be working with Scroll Cinema today.
So if you haven't created an alt account
yet you can follow that link there.
It should also be in the chat.
And if you run into any trouble
creating an account, just let me know.
And while as you get up there, I'll
just go through these introductory slides.
Okay, so a little bit about me.
My name is Artemia.
I'm a software developer and creative
technologist currently based in Italy.
Formerly
sponsored.
Sponsored contributed to WordPress,
which is a background
that I have taken into
developing these tools
to create scrolling animations
which are now my passion.
Modern ghost, which is
an example of scrolling,
is in the Electronic
Literature Collection, volume four.
Since then, I've been working
on Systemizing
set of tools in order to make it easy
for anyone to create scrolling
and apparently developing scroll cinema,
which is used for creating
scroll difference
in amount of web content.
And so our agenda for today, I'll give
a brief introduction to what scrolling is.
Then we'll dive
into the meat of the presentation
or the workshop rather, which is a walk
through scroll cinema.
I have a little bit of structure,
but I also want to just leave
it open to your
questions and what have you.
Hopefully you've
you have a text
that you would like to work with.
If not, we can spend a few minutes
and find some texts for people
you know, some poems or
what have you that we can play with.
And at the end,
I will try to wrap up with some ideas
regarding what the principles
of scrolling might be,
which I have some ideas on,
but I'm still discovering myself.
So with that being said,
I think it would be nice
to take a look of a few quick
examples of scrolling.
Just sort of set the set the stage.
So I've actually put together
a first volume
of online magazine called Scroll
on Online Anthology, which you can find
on the homepage of Alt Salt.
That's
where this nice little image comes from.
And there are some contributors
from the electronic literature community
as well as a couple of students.
Scroll cinema
has been using a couple of the classrooms
over the past semester or two.
And just to give you an idea
of the breadth, what can be done here.
So there's some sound here.
I don't know if that will play.
You can play with it as you'd like.
So the idea behind scrolling right.
We scroll.
Things happen.
There are animations going on.
It's scrolling is a very easy,
intuitive interface or way to interface
with an electronic literature work
because it's very visual, really.
The possibilities are very open
ended in terms of what can be done.
We can add simple interactivity
to create engaging experiences, and
you can borrow from the esthetic
languages
of film and comics and video games.
And because it's visually based like this,
there's just so many things
you can do with scrolling, right?
And I think
when it comes to electronic literature,
it solves a lot of user experience issues
with it in terms of people not knowing
how to navigate different interfaces
and things like that.
So, yeah, I think this particular flavor
of electronic literature
has a lot of potential in terms
of being a commercial frontier, as well
as being a gateway for a lot of folks
to get into electronic literature.
Here's a student piece
that will just get really quickly.
As you see,
these three pieces I'm showing
are completely different from each other.
They're all just using scrolling.
But in terms of like visual esthetic
and how they use the space,
all very, very different.
So that's something
I find really exciting about this space
and why I'm happy to excited
to share it with all of you.
Okay.
So I encourage you to take a look
more at scrolling.
It's on the homepage of Alt Salt,
the soft launch
right now
actually, during this conference.
Oh, I should also paste the link
to the workshop folder.
Sorry about that.
There's a folder here with these slides
and with the
and with the workshop guide,
which has some valuable links in there.
Okay.
All right.
And so with that
we can move on to a scroll cinema.
So scroll cinema is a two on building
to help make scrolling to create scrolling
where it's easy and scroll down there,
not just scroll cinema works.
There are also people who have done scroll
emission, doing custom code,
or perhaps other tools.
We've all seen editorial landing
pages, right?
All seen also like things like snowfall
in New York time pieces by Bloomberg.
But yeah, it's just what
you think of as scrolling and cool
things happening.
That being said,
Scroll Cinema is a tool to make creating
the experience is easy.
It currently has feature with parity
with a modern ghost, and there's a
gameplay logic system for interactivity,
and that's workflows coming in the future.
It's under continuous development,
and the core editor experience is
very functional,
is ready to be used for experimentation
and for projects of up to a few minutes.
In these.
Also, as mentioned, it was recently
used in a couple of college courses
I'm really excited about
is used for education.
Assistant Professor at Wayne University,
use it for
his immersive Media production class
and you can read the quote there.
There's a easy way for students
to get engaged and to start creating
mobile specific narratives.
So really excited about people
starting to pick up the tool.
Okay.
And so with all of that, please
let me know if you have any questions
as well about that or at any point
during the during this workshop.
But if everyone has a scroll
cinema account,
we can just start diving in
and playing with the tool.
So I tried to make it very simple to use.
It's like
a combination or a cross between unity
and the after effects
if you use either of those programs.
But once you get into your dashboard,
if you go to add new scrolling,
that will take you right to the
to the scroll cinema interface.
And here
this is very similar
to many other creative softwares.
You can resize the windows here.
You can also move
into like splitting things
and customizing the windows
if you'd like. And
for now we'll just leave this default
the way it is.
And has anyone not been successful
in creating a scroll account?
Looking at the chat?
Not successful.
Okay,
I will look into helping you in
just a moment
once we go into open workshop time.
So check.
Maybe check your spam.
That might be a
might be in there.
If not here, I can also.
Okay.
It looks like a couple of
people are having trouble here.
Nonacademic email address
to skip the filter.
Here.
I'm going to for a couple of folks,
they always take a couple of minutes
to a sense of
emails perhaps
okay.
During open workshop time I will try
to systemize or try to fix that.
Sorry about that.
I think you all for your patience
as we get this off the ground.
Okay, so I will walk through the
the basics of getting the starting to get
content placed and how to animate things.
And once we folks are starting to animate
things, I will come back and try to fix
your access. Sorry about that. Okay, so.
The the first thing to note is here
in the top
left corner we have this area
where we can place content.
So to get started just press this T
and we're going to hit default
to create a default text node.
And you'll see that here
in the preview window that pops up.
If you click on that or have it selected,
you'll be able to move this text
around the top and bottom boxes.
If you hover over them,
we'll move the content
lock to the X or Y axis.
And as we do
this, you'll notice
that we have all sorts of properties
here in the general inspector
that are changing.
So you can manipulate properties
either by moving them around in here
or by modifying the values here in the
in the general inspector,
if you hire the mouse
over the right side of the box,
you'll see that
this range selector opens up.
If you click and drag that,
that will allow you to minutely
change the values as well.
And I'm actually going to go down here
and give myself
the vampire, you know.
So that's going to be our title.
So that's a little bit on
how to place text.
We can also use this thing
called the shape tool
to place different kinds of
different kinds of shapes like squares
and triangles.
And change colors and things like that.
Some one thing that you can't change
aside from color,
you're using the general inspector
that you
that you can't change
with the preview window, but you can
with the general
inspectors like the opacity.
And so
yeah, for now,
just get used to placing some content.
We'll move into how to activate
scrolling and animation in just a moment.
I'll try to get these accounts
figured out
and let me know if you have any questions,
and see if you can start playing around
with some of your texts
that you hopefully brought.
And if not, I recommend
Annabel Lee by Edgar Allan Poe.
Or perhaps.
Yeah, just use.
Okay,
I'll stop sharing my screen
for just a moment
and try to get these accounts figured out.
Okay, let's look at one people
to get this figured out right now.
I'll try again in a bit.
If not, you could try using another email
perhaps.
Okay. All right.
So hopefully everyone has had a chance
to place a little bit of content.
I'm going to share my screen again
and move into showing how you can animate.
Okay.
So if you place some content
you should see over here that
you may have noticed that we have these
K and C buttons here which are currently
not active in order to activate them,
which is how we do animation.
You'll actually have to come over here
to the project window
and create the second button,
which is we'll create a reel
and we're going to go ahead and click
that and click the scroll.
And when something comes up in either
the hierarchy or the project window,
you can double click
and you can change the name.
I just going in and typing
what you'd like and pressing enter,
clicking outside of the box.
From the renaming story.
We have a lot of settings over here.
You don't need to touch any of them for
now, they're for the future.
But with
this selected
now, I'll introduce you to the
Or the screen, and I'll introduce you
to this new window down here
called the timeline.
If you click that to select a sequence
then select the really just created.
That will now allow us to animate.
So I'm going to select for example
this triangle here
I'm going to click the k.
We should just all click k for now k
sounds for keyframes and C for clips.
Editing for keyframes to start
is the easiest way to go.
And you'll see that
once we do that, this switches
to a diamond
and the two inputs turn to yellow.
So that means that we are currently
animating this property.
So if we click the diamond, that will set
the keyframe here on the timeline.
And if we click and drag the scrubber,
this represents
the different structures and time, right.
So I'm going to go ahead and
places that say 1.7 seconds.
And let's just
now move the triangle
going to move one up there.
And you'll see that this is now animating.
And just to give that
to see how that works, let's click
Save Draft
and then hit the preview button.
And you'll see first off that our layout
is exactly
as we made it in the preview window.
And if you scroll using your trackpad
or your mouse, you'll see that we are now
animating the content.
So that is the next step.
What?
Everyone get caught up with that?
How's everyone doing?
And feel free
to let me know if you have any questions.
And feel free to also start playing
with some of the other properties.
Sure, sure.
Yeah.
So to do that, I will put this over here.
You have to do that.
You need to create a reel.
So you'll press the second button
which will create a reel.
And then once that is created
here in the timeline view just select the
the thing you just created.
And once that's selected
this activates the timeline.
And you'll be able to come here and start
clicking the different properties.
I recommend sticking with the Kay from now
and then
modifying them.
Then you can press a diamond to
set the initial keyframe,
then move the scrubber to where you'd like
and just modify the property and will
automatically create a new keyframe.
Great to hear that you're in!
Jennifer.
Yeah, there may be something that I need
to check with on academic emails
or what have you.
So or mac com okay,
I will I may follow up with you later
to see how we can we can figure that out.
I'll give another a couple
of minutes to let folks
play around with animating that.
But yeah, to add an image file
you just press this button here,
which will allow you to import images
and you can search for
Aiken, search for anything
you'd like on your desktop.
Or you can also drag.
You can also drag files in from.
You can also drag files from here.
Let's see.
You can just drag files
into the project window and they'll import
once they're imported.
I believe you can click and drag here.
Is this work? Yeah.
You can click and drag an image
from the project
window into the hierarchy
and it will create an image node.
You can also press this image button here
that will create an image node.
And then you can
here click select
an image and pick any image that you've
that you've imported into the project.
So yeah that is how you can import images.
You can't seem to get back
to the project screen where I can create
a second item on the timeline.
I know it's so stupid.
Like I was just there,
like I'm looking at your screen right now
and you know where you see understory.
You've got dream too.
But the little clip with the
like the film strip,
I can't seem to locate that anymore
here.
Would you, would you be would you be
comfortable with sharing your screen?
And I can diagnose the issue?
Yeah, sure. Hang on.
Do I have permission to share my screen?
Let me just try to do that.
Can I give you permission?
Okay.
You said that you are having trouble
finding.
What?
Yeah. So under project.
You see, I've got, like, colors, dancers.
Those are two images I just imported.
But the last time I was able to do
experiment one and create
something like I, you know,
I animated the rectangle,
where is the little film clip thing
so that I can create like experiment
two and create a second animation.
Oh, okay. Yeah.
Hover
your mouse over the top right of that.
That window. Oh. Oh there.
Okay. All right. Thank you very much.
There we go. And then no problem.
Thank you
I'll stop sharing. Appreciate that.
Yeah okay.
You were to creating two different
two different reels.
I just thought I would,
I thought I would create anyway,
I just wanted to experiment, and it was.
Okay. Cool. Yeah. Yeah, yeah. If you.
So the starts move
into a slightly more advanced territory.
But yeah, if you, if you switch one
to time instead of a scroll.
So this is one of the things
that's powerful about scroll cinema is
you can have one primary reel
that's like the scrolling thing,
and then you can have other things
that are animating simultaneously.
So for example
let me do this, I will create
just because you brought me more.
Oh sorry.
Okay.
So let me do what I did there again.
So this is slightly more advanced,
but since you're doing it
maybe other folks are also doing it.
So here are my story.
And I'm going to create another reel.
And I'm going to call this do this a b.
Have this be a time reel.
I'm just going to call this like loop.
And I'm going to click this button here
I'm going to split.
The score is.
So I have two timelines now.
And I'm going to select the loop.
So now this is a separate animation
from the.
I'm going to do.
So you can see this more easily.
So this is a separate animation from the
the story animation.
And I'm going to fade
this rectangle in and out.
So let's whoops.
If you ever do something
you don't want to do you can also do
controller commands and go backwards
like many other creative softwares.
So yeah, I have to work on documentation
and getting all the hotkeys
and things in here.
But yeah, so
the documentation is forthcoming.
But that being said, I have the second
timeline over here and so I'm going to
click this window.
This little green dot symbolizes
which timeline you're working with.
And I'll
modify the opacity on the rectangle.
We'll start at a one
and then bring it down to zero.
And then
if you scroll up and down in the timeline,
you'll zoom in and out.
That's another thing,
and we'll fade it back in like that.
That can actually play us a play button
here.
We'll we'll be able to preview
what that looks like.
Stop that and I'll save it.
And this is playing automatically okay.
We'll also set this time
real to play on start.
And we'll set out to loop.
So we'll refresh the project page.
And so now you'll see that this
this animation is happening.
And then we're scrolling independently
of it.
So yeah that's just
nice to know
in terms of how you can start to build
complex animations using Scroll cinema.
And I should mention
also that there's a YouTube
series
that goes into more depth on models.
Here.
I'll show you where you can get to it.
If you go to com
and go to Scroll Cinema.
There's an introduction here.
There's me with my talking head.
And so this is part of a series.
And in every one of these videos
there's a link here.
So that will lead you
to the full playlist.
So yeah this goes is a
this is a very granular
sort of walkthrough of all the features.
Right.
In my experience, having the workshop
be a little bit more interactive
times, the better depending on how people,
how quickly people folks learn.
But yeah.
So that is a bit about the YouTube
tutorial series you can check out
at your leisure.
How's everybody doing?
Are there any questions so far?
Another thing I can show is
if you take a look at the workshop
folder, you'll see that there is this.
Am I still sharing my screen?
Yes. No.
Oh, sorry about that.
Did everyone see how to access the
how to access the YouTube series,
or did I not show
that?
It's all that?
Okay, perfect.
Okay, so if you go to the workshop folder,
you'll see that there's a folder for
getting started with Scroll Cinema Assets.
If you click into that,
you'll see that there's
this Scroll Cinema Project file.
So you can export and import projects
from school cinema.
I recommend if you're about to make any
big changes to your projects
to create a backup, but that means also
that you can share projects,
and in particular
this one if you want to load it
and take a look at it, see
how Modern Ghost is put together.
And so I'm going to actually download this
and import it right now.
And I'll have all the assets
from those tears as well.
If you want to play with them
they should be in there.
Okay I'll paste the room.
Just a moment.
In any case, they're all inside this
project file.
So I'm going to go ahead and import this
so I can show you
what a.
What a complex project looks like.
Where is where are my downloads.
Okay.
All the assets are in here.
So if you go into a modern ghost assets,
you'll see
all the images
and the audio such that we use to make it.
Okay.
So this is done.
And you go ahead and import.
The Scroll Cinema Project file.
Note that this also exports the HTML,
so your projects don't need to stay on.
Also,
this convenient for me to be able
to kind of help
folks with the tools
we're getting off the ground.
And yeah,
that being said,
you can export the HTML and take this
and publish it on a personal website
wherever you like.
Okay.
So yeah, I'd like to show you what a bit
of a more complex project looks like.
So I mean, with the animation of positions
and you can animate the opacity
in much the same way as I just showed.
And just like these basic nodes
that I've already showed you
how to do,
you can actually do quite a lot.
And it's really about,
you know,
putting these concepts
together to tell stories.
So here's a modern ghost.
It's a fairly big, robust project.
There's a lot of things going on here.
But yeah, it's
just a matter of moving images
and fading things in and out.
And all that.
So yeah,
I think I should go over conceptually
is that I've been asked in the past,
so how do you create more scroll
when you're working with scroll cinema?
And the key thing to keep in mind
is that this here,
the preview is like the stage, right?
And all of the nodes,
all the content, it always exists.
And what we're actually doing with Scroll
Cinema is this just animation software.
And we're just moving things on
and off the stage,
and all the content always exists, right?
So the fact that we're scrolling
is actually an illusion, right?
We're just using their scroll
input to advance an animation.
Right? So that being said, I think that
what I found to be really
effective is giving the solution
of like scrolling through space.
Right. And
and yeah, so that's just the thing
to grasp, conceptualize.
You're working with school cinema.
It's just one big animation
and a lot of school cinema
or making scrolling nations
thinking through, okay, what does the
what is the experience or pacing like
as I move through as well as a piece?
There are some advanced concepts
which I may go into depending on
how everyone's doing pulling, changing,
swipe, direction, going from the Y
to the access, for example, and also
auto playing through animations, right.
To give sort of create cinematic sequences
while folks are scrolling through.
But yeah, those are
that's just the illustrate a little bit
about what you can do with the tool.
Okay.
Let me go check out the chat.
How are we doing?
Do we have any questions?
Should I just start placing content
as if it were a real project?
You're trying to find the chat here.
Once.
Okay. Let's see.
After last year's workshop
was made a piece and that's in the.
Yes, yes.
Mark helped a lot with
with initial
when it was in a much earlier state.
So a huge thanks to Mark
and to the team there
for helping to solidify
a bit of the user workflows.
So yeah, once exported to HTML,
are the animations handled by JavaScript?
CSS file is eligible as well
or should just happen
in Scroll cinema project
with the clean export.
So the animations are handled in JS.
So pixie is the rendering engine.
It's all in JavaScript
and are the eligible files.
Actually
I mean you can go in and edit them.
I suppose it
it probably be best to edit them in scroll
cinema.
There's a lot of mechanics happening in there to make the animations work and such.
Yeah, it's yeah just works.
It creates JSON
and then through the player engine
it just renders
and move things around and CJS.
So yeah, I would say in Integral Cinema.
And Katelyn, you said yes, that would be
cool and great for the recording.
After, what were you referring to
when you were saying,
should I just go ahead and try to place
this as if it was a real project?
I was just I would. Okay.
But I mean, that's
just my thought about it.
Okay.
Yeah, I'm happy to go ahead and do that.
I can do that for like
the next ten minutes or so and then we can
I can start talking
about the principles of scrolling
if we can start thinking
about what those might be.
And yeah.
And wrap up any questions.
Okay.
So I'm going to go ahead and place a
create a new scrolling.
I'm also going to show the very beginning
of a modern ghost, in case anyone hasn't
seen it, just to give an idea
of what we're building.
Okay, so this is the piece
that where Scroll Cinema
was essentially born.
So here we come in with these introductory
splash sequences.
We have a screen to test the sound.
We press the start button.
We go into this experience.
There's a tutorial on YouTube
that goes through the entire
process of how to create a splash sequence
like that.
We're going to start here
when the story proper begins, where
we're placing some content and
we have these parallax effects and such.
Okay, so
let me hop back over to the scroll cinema
here.
And I did download these project files
just not too long ago.
Let's see where they are.
I can just download them again from here.
Okay.
So I'm going to
I have a bunch of image files here
which I'm going to import
into Scroll Cinema just by great
dragging and dropping it
like the first six
pages.
Yeah.
One thing to note as projects
get bigger and there's a lot of things
going on, it's good to name your assets.
You know, 001002 or have you
break them out into pages and such.
I'll go into a little bit
more depth on that tomorrow
during the storyboarding workshop.
So if this interests you,
I'd highly encourage you
to check out that workshop
tomorrow. Same time.
And so yeah.
With that being said, let's
go ahead and start placing this content.
Okay.
So we have so we're going to create
the first page of a modern ghost.
We're going to click
and drag this light bulb in here.
We also have this part one text.
Oh. Another thing working with scroll
emission really benefits
from especially in school cinema,
from storyboarding ahead of time,
especially as projects
that bigger and more complex.
And it helps to think through
the different kinds
of interactions and animations
that you can do to express a story.
Right.
So all right, here
we have the first page of
the Modern Ghost Place.
I like to place the things,
like I said, into pages and groups.
So we're going to actually give this a hit
the group button, have those two things
selected and click parent Group.
They'll place them
both into into that group.
And then I animate the group when I'm
when I'm building scrolling,
when I'm building scrolling.
And then sort of the groups
are the main thing I move and then I
animate things within those
with those within those broad strokes.
Right.
So I'm actually going to also place
all these into a folder.
So I just selected all of the images.
I press the folder button
and it moves all of them into there.
I'll double
click the folder call it artwork.
Close
that for now so I can easily access
the release button.
I'm going to create a scroll reel.
We're going to call that story.
And we're going to select story here.
And we're going to start animating this.
You can animate this using
key frames or clips.
I'll just use keyframes
to keep it simple for now.
Okay.
We'll place one keyframe at the zero mark
and then we'll go 1.7 seconds.
So I found that going 1920 pixels
for every 1.7
seconds is a good rule of thumb
for doing in terms of sensitivity.
I may go into this,
but just know that
the longer
something takes here in the timeline,
the more swipe after it will take
for someone to scroll through it, right?
I found that
1.7 seconds is a good rule of thumb.
Okay, so we have that.
We're going to place a text node
into here.
And notice
that we actually want the text to appear
underneath the light bulb and such.
So let's just move this text down
into the second page.
And we have the text for Modern Ghost
here.
It's going to copy and paste this in.
A note regarding text.
By default it's
we just have a one long paragraph.
If you'd like to enable word wrap
you can just press this button here
and that will enable that.
We have a little notice here.
There's like some inconsistency on Firefox
or what have you with line breaks.
And most other browsers work
pretty well. But.
Yeah,
let me just lower the font size on here.
And let's take the word down a little bit.
Okay.
So there's a little bit of that.
We're going to need to actually move this
a little bit further.
So we'll move it to 3.4 seconds.
Move this to 3840.
So how I work how I typically work
with scroll
cinema is I.
Build a build a project up
page by page like this.
Let's add an image or.
Look for
the first train of this
where the image go up there.
And when the the y over here
like so.
You can also copy and paste nodes.
So I'm going to hit
command C and command v.
We can also do control C or control V.
If you're on windows
place this over here.
Make them a little bigger
little bigger okay.
Starting to get a rough idea
of what this project looks like.
What save draft
and take a look at the take a look at it.
That's looking.
Looking a bit rough, but
getting the idea down.
One thing I can show is how to
creating parallax effects. So.
I think,
yeah,
I typically do this with this inkblot.
I think it's this one.
I'll just make it smaller.
Okay.
So we want to give a sense of depth
as we're moving through this page.
Right.
So I'm going to at this point
start adding making this inkblot
and this part of the group.
Right.
So it's moving with everything else.
But I also want to animate it
so it moves a little bit faster right.
So I'll anime it like so.
And now when we swipe
we'll get this nice little effect of this.
Of the sink plot.
Let's actually keep it moving
until the end of the animation
so it appears off screen.
So then that should be pretty seamless.
Modify this a little bit more.
Also,
you'll notice if you click a keyframes
and what have you,
you'll be able to edit them
using the their values using the Timeline
Inspector here in the corner.
So I want to edit
the value of this keyframe
a little bit more. So.
So we save this, refresh the page
and scroll.
And then we can have
our nice little parallax
effect of the ink blot.
Hopping back over in the chat,
can the words themselves
be animated in any way?
Let's see.
So the first thing that comes to mind is.
You can animate the scale,
the rotation, the opacity of any text.
I'm working on more robust tools
where you can maybe
take, say, a paragraph and slice
all the individual words.
Right.
For now, if you want to animate
individual words, you just have to create
a few different text nodes.
So we can say for example above.
The. Let's just
animate their positions.
I'm not sure if this is
what you had in mind, but.
The other is
one way that you can animate
individual words.
So here we find that
those words fly off on their own,
and you can change their color
or their opacity or what have you.
If you spend time like animating
the individual words of a paragraph,
placing
the things that you can accomplish.
Lots of effects right now.
Yeah, like I said,
it's on the roadmap to create helpers
to make that process easier.
But yeah, if you just patient
and replace all the text,
you can animate it in many different ways.
Does that answer your question, Emily,
or is there anything I'm missing?
Feel free to hop on to voice and ask
if you'd like to clarify.
Yeah, that's what I was asking.
Yep. Yeah,
I think this is so I used
I had a different version of cinema.
This is like the version
that I can finally released publicly,
but previously it was a
plugin that I can redistribute.
But I don't know if anyone seen revision
the word,
but we do a lot of that,
just like there's a paragraph.
And Warren who designed it.
He loves to animate words,
particularly in different ways.
So there's some like he's
an accomplished these same effects
you see in the silver here using skills
right now. Right.
Just haywire and have all these words
flying these letters, individual orders
flying around
does something that's totally possible.
Okay.
So let me come back to my slides
for a moment.
I'd like to
philosophize a
little
bit about the principle of discrimination.
Oh, something else about alt salt. Yeah.
The platform.
It's an early access as well.
So it's a community website focused
on high fidelity, innovative formats.
So Zion's Illit, Scroll Nation,
and the idea is to get more people easily
creating,
engaging and also make it super easy
and build community around that.
So, one idea that I'd like to
have is to do more community projects
like Scroll Nation.
So yeah, looking forward
to doing more of that.
So also as well as in development.
And so with that being said,
some principles of Scroll Nation.
Okay.
So I'm still very much discovering
what works and what doesn't myself.
I'll be going into more on that during
the storyboarding workshop tomorrow.
And you can
even take a look at my piece
when I Fall Asleep in the Scroll Mission
anthology and let me know what is working
and what's not working there.
I have some ideas myself,
but that being said, get Scroll Nation.
We can just borrow from game design
principles, art principles, design
principles that the nation principles,
Gestalt principles, what have you.
I think the interesting thing
about scrolling is they can mix
all of these things together
with the secret sauce of
just making the primary mode
of interaction scrolling,
and that's sort of is the glue that holds
everything together.
But yeah, in any moment you can decide,
is it better for this moment to be text
or should it be images, or should
it just be sound or what have you?
So there's just a lot of potential there.
And so with a lot of user testing,
I started to think about,
okay, what are the things that make
scrolling nation then engaging?
And really they're just riffs off
on those previous disciplines, right?
But yeah, one thing is just movement
through space or continuous change.
So something about this infinite
scrolling concept, or the fact that folks
feel like their input impacts
the experience that makes it interactive.
I think that's very important.
So to always give users agency over,
okay, I scroll and this thing happens
and making sure that things are
always visually interesting,
and, and such.
Also giving that gives users a sense
of progression as they move through it.
So I think that continuous change
and user input is really important,
just like composition, visual composition,
what have you, how do you draw the eye
across the page?
We have an infinite canvas, right?
So you're not just thinking
about the square that you're in, but
like what comes after the square
and how you're really guiding the eye
and creating space across different panels
or across different pages.
Parallax,
nice uses of parallax gives sense of depth
to our scrolls
and also progression game design.
I do this in what I call
sleep as well as in modern use.
You start people somewhere familiar
and then you take them somewhere
unexpected, right?
So with the modern ghost, we press
the button, the camera starts distorting.
Folks, get interested
what is going on here?
Right?
And then we start scrolling vertically,
which people understand
with some parallax,
and then we scroll for.
And then we start moving in and out,
in and out on the Z axis.
And people are like,
oh, what is this? Right.
So just thinking about that, like,
how can you really surprise users
and keep them engaged by sort of
by varying how you present your content?
And lastly, multimedia storytelling,
I mean, we our books are no longer
printed, are no longer
in their printed page.
All you folks are in.
So you know this,
but we have audio, we have video,
we have, you know, artwork,
we have text that can be animated.
Just like really think about all the tools
that are disposal to
try to make our experiences
as, as engaging as possible.
So yeah,
I'll again dive into all this
a little bit more when we talk
about storyboarding for school
and how you can take
any story or idea that you have
and try to adapt it into scrolling
and think about all the possibilities
that you have at your disposal.
But yeah, so I would love to have a dialog
on the what you're discovering
as you're creating scrolling.
So, for example,
I'll just show this really quickly.
A student this past semester, they,
this is on the old salt home page.
This is an example of something they did,
and I had never thought to do this.
I don't know, this is just like frame
by frame animation from a camera.
I guess that they took the photos
from their cell phone.
And this is very different
than anything that I've done with scroll.
And I think this is really cool.
I think there's a lot of
potential here in terms of,
I don't know, I just I
just love the movement
and the colors and all and what have you.
And I really want to see like
this is developed a bit more.
So that being said, I think that the space
is wide open for experimentation.
There's a lot of cool things
that can be done.
We're just scratching the surface here.
And yeah,
I'd love to see what you all make.
And you know,
if more students in classrooms
get to use it creates student showcases
and just exchange ideas on the
on the things that we can do. So
that's what I have for now.
So we have any questions.
And if we don't have any questions,
I can dive in and maybe show
another couple of things in the other.
Feel free also
to come on boys,
if you would like to like to
share that way.
Yes, the aspect
ratio is fixed from all the screens are
now it is a 9 to 16.
It's reference resolution is 1080
by 1926 cells.
There are no parameters to explore
before exploring the HTML.
Whether or
are you trying to open it in browser?
It requires a web server.
So if you can just do a simple PHP server
or simple Python
server to run it locally,
maybe that's what it's missing.
You can't just double
click on the index.html work.
Yeah, that's because
that's because of the compression
and other things that it's
doing under the hood
to make it quick to run,
and which apparently requires
a web server.
So yeah, there's a very simple
PHP command to do that.
It's like a PHP
Python s then
127.00.1 colon
post name or port name.
So yeah.
Yeah.
Thanks to you, Matt.
I'm glad to hear that
you think the tool is excellent.
Yeah. Looking forward
to having you play around with it.
You can also find your discord in the
in the player
of the website
where there will be.
I'm hoping to do more events
and such there over the next few months.
But yeah, just sharing ideas projects
there to try to see the share ideas
on what we can make.
Yeah, something I should point out is
just a few other things
like we have other run.
I'll just demonstrate this really quick.
So here
I've initiated an auto run sequence.
So now when I start swiping,
anything that's configured in the other
end sequence will play automatically.
So that's how you mix cinematic sequences
in with scrolling sequences.
We also have this logic system
which will which can allow you to
to add
like click
events and other things like that.
That's the next major feature is shipping
this gameplay logic system
to make these
these scrolls very interactive.
But yeah.
So just keep in mind
that there is some programing logic type
stuff that you can do
inside of inside of the system.
Yeah.
Maybe I should actually demonstrate
that with a couple of minutes.
One thing you can do is create
sound effects.
So let me see.
Yeah.
Here's a nice little sound of that.
So I'm going to click I'm
going to drag this audio file in.
And I just added an action trigger.
This is a little bit more advanced
but I'm just showing
for curiosity's sake.
Chronically
go here to
we have this action trigger select
and we add a trigger.
At this point
we can select an audio action.
And we're going to select the target
of the audio file we just imported.
And we're going to have a play Audio.
I'm not sure if you'll be
able to hear this, but if I
now go ahead and preview this and scroll.
First off, the
this audio icon will appear in the corner
saying that you can press that
to activate the audio.
And if we scroll at that minute
that we cross this,
this action trigger,
the sound effect will play.
And we also have functionality
to activate these triggers.
And going in the forward direction
or, and, or in the reverse direction.
So we can tailor our experiences based on
whether people are going forward
or going backward, which is important
for creating immersive experiences.
So just wanted to give
a little brief introduction to the to the
to the logic system there.
Yeah,
yeah,
there seems to be so much room
for creativity with this tool.
Yeah.
The reason I created it
myself was just because, you know,
I wanted to have the flexibility of,
oh, say, I'm doing a comic,
I want to be able to put animation
in that comic,
and I want to be able
to have a dynamic soundtrack with that.
That's another thing. Dynamic soundtracks.
So I don't know
if I have an audio here, but,
we're about to run out of time,
but you can take a look at that in the
in the YouTube tutorial series.
Yeah, we can.
And also in one night.
Also, if we do a lot of this dynamic audio
where you move through and
like you have like the wind in one section
and you feed the wind out,
you bring in the traffic sounds
and what have you.
Evoking.
Cranky festival
I miss cranky festival, maybe I
and something that.
The the
the joke is going over my head.
Okay.
Very cool.
Oh please send me the link
or drop in the discord or something.
Yeah, I like scrolling things very much.
All right, I'll stop sharing my screen.
And the other last minute questions
were just about at about time.
I can also hang around
for a few more minutes.
I don't know if we have the room available
on what have you.
I'm happy to stick around as well.
Thank you so much.
Cranky Festival.
Thank you so much for coming.
We do need to close the room
and then reopen it between sessions
for the recordings,
but if there's one more comment, go ahead.
Yeah, I have no additional comments.
Just thank you so much for tuning in,
and I hope to see you at the storyboarding
for School Workshop tomorrow.